Main navigation
---------------

Search 

[](#)Submit

Privacy Policy
==============

#### Information about our Organization about Websites

MV Transportation, Inc. ("MV") is providing this Privacy Policy to give you notice of our practices and of the choices you can make about the way your information is collected online and how that information is used. Please read this Privacy Policy carefully and revisit this page from time to time to review any changes that may have been made.

MV may amend this Privacy Policy at any time by posting the amended terms on this site. All amended terms automatically take effect on the date set forth in the posted Privacy Policy, unless otherwise specified.

#### Sites Covered by this Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy applies to all MV owned websites and domains (collectively, "MV Websites"). The MV Websites may provide links to third-party websites for your convenience and information. If you access those links, you will leave the MV Websites. We do not control those sites or their privacy practices, which may differ from our own privacy practices. This Privacy Policy does not cover any personal data that you choose to give to third parties. We do not monitor or control the information collected by such sites or the privacy practices of any third parties, and we are not responsible for their practices or the content of their sites.

#### Types of Information We Collect and Use

In this policy, "personal information" or "personal data" means information about an identifiable individual that is subject to protection under the law in the jurisdiction in which you reside. In some jurisdictions, "personal information" or "personal data" will not include business contact information. MV collects information through a variety of different ways and for different purposes as described in the table below.

|     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- |
| **Source of Information** | **Types of Information** | **Purpose for Use of Information** |
| **Information You Provide Through The MV Websites** | * Identifiers, such as name, email address, phone number, that you submit to us when you fill out any of our forms available through the MV Websites<br>* Preferences, such as information concerning preferences for certain routes, times of travel, preferred experience on the buses | * To process your requests or inquiries<br>* To improve our services and our business<br>* To improve our website |
| **Information We Collect When You Use The MV Websites** | * Cookies or other digital markers that the MV Websites automatically collect (such as browser type, Internet service provider, platform type, internet protocol (IP) addresses, referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp)<br>* Google Analytics, such as geographic and demographic information | * We do not associate this information with any personally identifiable information about you. We aggregate this information for reporting about the MV Websites, to analyze trends, diagnose problems with our server, administer the MV Websites, track user movement and use, and gather broad demographic information<br>* To improve our websites<br>* To improve our services and our business<br>* To protect and ensure the technical functioning of our websites and develop new services |
| **Information From Sources Other Than MV Websites** | * Identifiers, such as name and contact information from our customers or from individual riders that are obtained through survey results or feedback provided by individual riders<br>* Sensory information, such as video images captured through cameras installed in our vehicles | * To improve our services and business<br>* For product and services improvement and development<br>* To address any rider complaints<br>* To address driver or passenger behavior<br>* To comply with legal obligations |

#### Sharing of Information

No Sale of Personal Information: MV does not and will not sell your personal information. During the last 12 months, MV has not disclosed personal data to third parties for their own useexcept MV has disclosed limited personal information related to riders in response to (a) legal process, such as a subpoena or discovery request in civil litigation; (b) government audits; or (c) requests by child protective services agencies and other governmental authorities in the context of an investigation**.**In these situations, the personal information disclosed generally has been limited to identifiers, such as the rider’s name, contact information, and pick-up address.

#### Your California Privacy Rights

This section of the Privacy Policy applies only to riders and other individual users of our services who reside in the State of California and whose personal information we use for MI’s own business purposes (“California Consumers”).

1. **_Right_ to Know**

California Consumers have the right to submit a verifiable request to know:

* The categories and specific pieces of personal information that MV has collected about them;
* The categories of sources from which MV collected the personal information;
* The categories of personal information that MV sold or disclosed to a third party (other than a service provider) for a business purpose and the categories of recipients of that information; and
* The business or commercial purposes for MP’s collection, disclosure, or sale of the personal information.

1. **Right To Delete**

* California Consumers have the right to submit a verifiable request for deletion of their personal information that MV has collected from the Consumer.

How to Exercise Your Rights

1. **Making Requests**

MV will respond to requests in accordance with applicable law if it can verify the identity of the individual submitting the request. California Consumers can exercise their rights in the following ways:

* Complete the online request form available here: [https://mvtransit.com/contact-us/passenger-feedback](https://mvtransit.com/contact-us/passenger-feedback) and/or [https://mvtransit.com/contact-mvtransit](https://mvtransit.com/contact-mvtransit);
* Contact by telephone: (877) 687-2338

1. **Requests By Authorized Agents**

You can have an authorized agent submit a California Consumer Privacy Act (“CCPA”) request to us on your behalf by (a) providing us with a written authorization signed by you that designates the agent as your authorized agent for purposes of a coca request; (b) verifying your identity directly with us; and (c) directly confirming with us that the agent is authorized to submit the request.

1. **How We Will Verify Your Requests**

To prevent anyone other than you, or your authorized agent, from exercising the right to know or the right to delete with respect to your personal information, we follow procedures to verify your, or your agent’s, identity. This process seeks to confirm that the person making a request is the person about whom we have collected personal information or that person’s authorized agent. The verification process involves matching data points that you provide with your request against information about you we already have in our records and that we have determined to be reliable for purposes of verifying your identity. We will use information you provide in your completed request form to verify your identity, and we may request additional information if necessary to complete the verification process.

#### Additional Rights for California Consumers

1. **The Company’s Non-Discrimination Policy**

California Consumers have the right not to be subject to discriminatory treatment by MV for exercising their privacy rights under the CCPA, and MV will not discriminate on that basis. However, MV may charge a California Consumer a different price or rate or provide a different level or quality of goods or services if the difference is reasonably related to the value provided to the California Consumer by the Consumer’s Personal Information.If MV does so, it will provide Consumers with any legally required notice.

1. **Your ‘Do Not Track’ Browser Setting**

The site does not collect personally identifiable information about your online activities over time and across third-party websites or online services. We do not currently respond to web browser “do not track” (“DNT”) signals or other mechanisms that indicate your preference for not having information collected over time and across different web sites following your visit to one of our sites.DNT is a preference you can set in your browser’s settings to let the websites you visit, including the site, know that you do not want the sites collecting your personal information. If we do so in the future, we will describe how we do so in this Privacy Policy.You can also visit [https://allaboutdnt.com/](https://allaboutdnt.com/) to learn more.

#### Children's Privacy

MV is committed to protecting the privacy needs of children and we encourage parents and guardians to take an active role in their children's online activities and interests. MV does not knowingly collect information from children under the age of 13 and MV does not target its websites to children under 13.

#### Your Choices and Opting Out

If MV uses your personal information in a manner not described in this Privacy Policy, such as providing you with promotional communications, we will notify you of such use and give you the opportunity to opt-out of such use. You may opt-out of receiving communications from us by emailing us at [Webmaster@MVTransit.com](mailto:Webmaster@MVTransit.com). Please type "Opt-Out" in the subject line.

#### Keeping Your Information Secure

MV stores personal information on our servers in the United States of America. MV does not guarantee or warrant the security of our servers nor can we guarantee that information you supply through the MV Websites will not be intercepted while being transmitted over the Internet. We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal data submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it.

#### Business Transitions

In the event that MV goes through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company or sale of all or a portion of its assets, your personal information will likely be among the assets transferred.

#### Terms and Conditions

If you choose to visit the MV Websites, your visit and any dispute over privacy is subject to this Privacy Policy and our Terms and Conditions, including, but not limited to, disclaimers of warranty, limitations of liability, and arbitration of disputes.

#### CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY

If we change this Privacy Policy, we will post those changes on this page and update this Privacy Policy modification date above. If we materially change this Privacy Policy in a way that affects how we use or disclose your personal information, we will provide a prominent notice of such changes and the effective date of the changes before making them.

#### Contacting us

We value your opinions. If you have comments or questions about this Privacy Policy or to advise us of a concern relating to the handling of your personal information, please send us an e-mail at [mailto:mv.communication@mvtransit.com](mailto:mv.communication@mvtransit.com). If your concern is privacy related, please type "Privacy" in the subject line of your e-mail.

trusted by

MV Kudos

"MV has demonstrated an ongoing commitment to customer service and operational efficiency. We are pleased to extend our partnership with a shared focus on improving and enhancing mobility throughout the community."

**– Adrian Aguilar,** _Santa Clarita City Transit Manager_

“MV has consistently demonstrated its reliability and commitment to providing positive customer service.”

**– Mike Greenwood,** _Chief Operations Officer, Access Services_ 

“MV Transportation is safe, reliable and responsive. Putnam County has developed a partnership that provides affordable and consistently dependable transportation services for our residents. The personal attention to every detail helps make my job as the transit manager easy. MV is extraordinary in every aspect of transit service.”

**– Vincent Tamagna,** _Chairman Transportation Advisory /Director Transportation, Putnam County, NY_

“MV’s more than 15-year commitment to the success of our system is critical as we continue our work to grow ridership and improve mobility throughout the Tri-Valley community.”

**– Michael Tree,** _LAVTA Executive Director_ 

SEE WHAT WE'RE UP TO:[](https://twitter.com/realMVTransit/)[](https://www.facebook.com/Mvtransit/)[](https://www.linkedin.com/company/mv-transportation)
